

### Profile

I'm an experienced Software Engineer, with a passion for learning and building products both in the web and mobile spaces. I strive to convert ideas into real life products that are customer-centric. My expertise revolves around the following development stacks Vue.js,React Native, Laravel and Express

# Employment History

## Full-Stack Engineer at Ralphowino Consulting, Nairobi

April 2018 — September 2019

- Refactored the Laravel application codebase into a back-end and front-end project from Laravel blades to a Vue.js app and Laravel APIs
- Set up automated deployment using Jenkins and Gitlab pipelines.
- Performed code reviews and pair programming sessions.
- Worked on implementing Vue.js components logic.
- Client-server setup on AWS and customer support.
- Wrote tests both for the front-end (Unit and E2E using Jest) and the back-end (using JUnit).
- Implemented task queuing with Redis and Supervisor.
- Containerization with Docker for easy deployment (Laradock).

### Senior Software Engineer at Solutech Limited, Nairobi

September 2019 — April 2022

- Database restructuring and optimization to support the growing client base.
- Introduced Vue.js and React for front-end development to utilize the powerful features provided by both libraries.
- Implemented critical product features that were key to the business growth (Order Management, Logistics Management, Promotions, Dynamic surveys).
- Implemented an internal Human Resource Management system with Laravel and Vue.js
- Conducted pair programming sessions with interns and junior developers.
- Insightful report generation and automatic scheduling.
- Dashboard visualization in graphical formats with data drill down.
- Documentation of APIs and system functionality.
- Handled integration with third-party systems (Sage, ERP, SAP).
- Wrote tests both for the front-end (Unit and E2E using Jest) and the back-end (using JUnit).
- Collaborated with the mobile team, design team, and data team.

### Senior Software Engineer Consultant at Fourth Profile, Nairobi

May 2022 — Present

• Engineering Consultant for their platform Fourth Profile.

#### **Details**

Nairobi

Kenya

0711536733

dng.ngatia@gmail.com

#### Links

Github

LinkedIn

Portfolio

Pluralsight

Stack Overflow

#### **Skills**

Git

JavaScript

React, Next, React Native

SQL

PHP, Laravel

Vue, Nuxt

Node, Express

**Automated Testing** 

CSS, Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS

Pinia

Docker

Redis

Rabbit MQ

**AWS** 

#### **Hobbies**

Cycling, Nature Walk

### Languages

English

Swahili

- Convert system requirements into features and milestones
- Coordinate with UI/UX team in implementing feature design in Vue and Tailwind CSS.
- Implement back-end features in Laravel/Lumen
- Writing front-end test in Jest and back-end tests in JUnit.
- Coordinate testing of the MVP before going to production.
- Automating deployment with github actions (CI/CD)
- Server setup and project dockerization and containerization.
- Setting up server queuing with RabbitMQ

# Senior Software Engineer at Myhealth Africa, Nairobi

October 2022 — Present

- Technical lead in the development of the Myhealth international treatment platform
- API's development in Laravel and Lumen
- Frontend development in Vue.js and Tailwind CSS
- CI/CD with Github actions
- Part of the development team of the internal IMS (Integrated Management System) for running internal operations from customer support, HR Management, Finance and Leads and Sales automation.
- Automated testing (Unit and Feature tests) with PHP Unit and Jest for frontend tests.

### Education

Bsc. Computer Science, Egerton University, Nakuru

September 2014 — March 2018

Second class honours

### **◄** References

**Timothy Oriedo from Predictive Analytics Lab** 

timoriedo@gmail.com

**Derdus Mosoti from Fourth Profile** 

derduskenga@gmail.com

**Kelvin Kibugi from Empact Solutions** 

info@empact.co.ke